this video is sponsored by brilliant hey
guys this looks like a fun one it wants
to know what is the Shaded area and it's
telling us that the largest semicircle
and the smallest semicircle have the
same Center first let's look at the
radius of the smaller semicircle and
let's call it little r and then let's
look at the radius of the larger
semicircle and call it Big R when set up
like this these form a right triangle
with this distance of two so that means
we can do Pythagorean theorem it'll be
2^2 + little R2 = Big R 2 we can
simplify this we can make 2^2 equal to 4
and let's get both of these RS onto the
same side of the equation we can
subtract little R 2 from both sides and
that'll give us 4 is equal to Big R 2
minus little R 2 and this looks
important let's put a box around it this
blue area is split up into two sections
there's the left area and the right area
and if we add these together we'll have
the total blue area so to calculate this
left side it's going to be the larger
semicircle minus the smaller semicircle
and the equation for both those
semicircles is pi/ 2R 2 and then on the
right hand side we can do this
semicircle minus this semicircle so now
let's find this radius it's going to be
capital r so we can plug that in right
here and then to find the radius of this
one the diameter of this one is the Big
R plus the little r so the radius is
going to be Big R plus little r / 2 so
we can put that right here and then for
this semicircle it's going to be the
same diameter Big R plus little r so the
radius would be Big R R plus little r /
2 and last we have this little guy which
has a radius of little r now we have our
left and our right so we just want to
add all of these together let's
rearrange things a little bit these two
match and one's positive and one's
negative so they're going to cancel each
other out and that'll just leave us with
Pi / 2 big r^ 2 minus P piun / 2 little
R 2 both of these have a common factor
of Pi / 2 so let's factor that out and
Pi / 2 * r^ 2 gives us the first term
and then we subtract little R 2 to get
the second term so we're left with < / 2
* big r^ 2 - little R 2 and if you look
at our box we already know what big r^ 2
minus little R 2 is it's equal to four
so in the place of this we can
substitute four we can bring the divided
two in here with the four and then 4 / 2
is equal to 2 and now we have the answer
to our question the area is equal to 2
pi square units and we can put a box
around it I think this is a brilliant
problem speaking of brilliant I want to
give you guys an update on brilliant
I've been going through this for over a
month now and I absolutely love it there
are thousands of interactive lessons in
math data analysis programming AI all
kinds of different things it's the best
way to learn it's not about memorizing
steps it's about understanding the
concepts I was originally excited about
the math courses yet the last two weeks
I've been exploring other topics right
now I want to focus on how AI works I
feel like AI is going to play a huge
role in content Creation in the future
so I kind of want to learn how it works
I just started this course how language
models work I've been able to learn how
they build vocabulary and choose the
next word and there's also a part that
shows the differences based on what you
use for training data for example the
difference between training on Taylor
Swift lyrics versus a cookbook I'm
pretty excited to see what comes next if
you want to try a brilliant for free for
30 days visit brilliant.org Andy or
click on the link in the description you
can also get 20% off an annual premium
plan how exciting